<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Defs>
	
	<Description>
		<li>Random Genetics Framework is designed to generate random genes for pawns based on your own conditions.</li>
		<li>Built with compatibility and ease of use in mind, this documentation should address any questions you have.</li>
	</Description>
	
	<ThingsYouCanDo>
		<li>Have a pawn receive 1 of multiple choices of genes. Or even multiple genes all at random.</li>
		<li>Generate a random gene based on various conditions like metabolism, exclusionTag, or if it has an ability or prerequisite.</li>
		<li>Generate random hair or skin colors that are all similar by RGB, Hue, Saturation, or Value.</li>
		<li>Have a set of genes that will only be used if a certain mod is active.</li>
		<li>Adjust weights and fillers so certain selections are more common than others or prevent a selection from even occurring..</li>
		<li>After the gene is added to a pawn, it will assign all the genes it was told to and then remove itself.</li>
	</ThingsYouCanDo>
	
	<ReasonsToUse>
		<li>You have over 5000 genes in your modlist and want more variety in your pawns.</li>
		<li>You want a Xenotype to be more diverse in genetics being chosen.</li>
		<li>You can't make up which gene you want to add to a Xenotype and want to add both.</li>
		<li>You want to add a gene to a xenotype but only when another mod is available, but you want to use another gene if it's not available.</li>
		<li>You like diversity and are tired of your Xenoptypes all having the same shade of green hair when there are over 300 different genetic hair colors</li>
		<li>You don't want to create an entirely new Xenotype to give a pawn a super special ultra instincts gene.</li>
	</ReasonsToUse>
	
	<UsingThisDocumentation>
		<li>The files numbered 01-04 can be copied and pasted into the Defs folder to see how they work for demonstration purposes.</li>
		<li>This file 00intro.xml and 05Notes.xml can not be copied into Defs. Rimworld will yell at you.</li>
		<li>The genes themselves have comments on how they are used.</li>
		<li>05Notes.xml contains extra information such as genes you should exclude from randomly generating or other miscellaneous things you can do.</li>
		<li>Alternatively, you can look at the genes used in the separate random genes mod.</li>
	</UsingThisDocumentation>
	
	<compatibility>
		<li>I haven't tested all 5000+ genes, but everything I've tested so far has worked.</li>
		<li>Compatible with Cherry Picker. Any genes included that you remove through Cherry Picker will not generate on pawns.</li>
		<li>This has compatibility with RedMattis' Big and Small - Framework. With their permission, I used their code for betterprerequisites to ensure compatibility</li>
		<li>This mod should be removable at any time. The genes on the pawns that were already spawned will not disappear.</li>
		<li>You will of course receive errors if your xenotypes are using any genes made using this when trying to spawn them.</li>
	</compatibility>
	
	
	<credits>
		<mods>
			<li>Goji's Fantasy Race: Merren</li>
			<li>Det's Xenotypes - Avaloi</li>
			
			<note>These mods were my main influence in creating this.
				They each had functions for creating their own random genes which showed me how to even start this mod. Thank you!</note>
		</mods>
		
		
		<author>
			<li>RedMattis</li>
			<note>Allowed me to use the code for their Big and Small - Framework mod</note>
		</author>
	
	</credits>

</Defs>